Texas College & University Systems Coordinating Board (UH) Records
University of Houston Libraries
Texas College & University Systems Coordinating Board (UH) Records
1965-1985
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Texas College and University System Coordinating Board
3.00 Linear Feet
The Coordinating Board, Texas College and University System, is a statutory board appointed by the Governor. It is responsible for statewide planning and policy-making to assure quality and efficiency in Texas higher education. The collection consists of Audit Reports, Correspondence, Board Minutes, Proposals, Reports, Rules and Regulations, Resolutions, and Statements.
1985-002
Historical Note
The Coordinating Board, Texas College and University System, is a statutory board appointed by the Governor. It is responsible for statewide planning and policy-making to assure quality and efficiency in Texas higher education. The Board's primary areas of responsibility are financial planning, senior colleges and universities, community colleges, and continuing education, health affairs, student services and campus planning.
Scope and Contents
This collection arrived at the archives in relatively good order, which has been maintained where possible. The collection consists of Audit Reports, Correspondence, Board Minutes, Proposals, Reports, Rules and Regulations, Resolutions, and Statements.
Forms part of the University Archives.
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Coordinating Board, Texas College and University System; Texas Higher Education Coordinating Board
Genre/Form of Material:
Administrative records; Correspondence; Minutes; Reports
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Acquisition
Detailed Description
- Administrative Records
  Arranged alphabetically, these records contain 122 folders of materials dating from 1967-1983. Overall, the original folder order has been maintained. This collection contains a wide range of materials relating to the administration of the Coordinating Board, Texas College and University System. The records consist of Audit Reports, Correspondence, Board Minutes, Proposals, Reports, Rules and Regulations, Resolutions, and Statements.
  - Coordinating Board: Acts & Bills (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Coordinating Board: Agendas, 1968-72, 75, 77 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Coordinating Board: Agenda Items (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Coordinating Board: Annual Report, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Coordinating Board: Annual Report, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Coordinating Board: Audit Report, August 31, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Coordinating Board: Audit Report, August 31, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Coordinating Board: Audit Report, August 31, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Coordinating Board: Audit Report, August 31, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Coordinating Board: Audit Report, August 31, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Coordinating Board: Audit Report, August 31, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Coordinating Board: Bond Resolutions: Memo to Gresham, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Coordinating Board: Certificate: Newton Gresham, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Coordinating Board: Compliance Agreement (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Board Members, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - J. K. Williams - Commissioner of Higher Education (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Coordinating Board: Correspondence - Newton Gresham, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Coordinating Board: Financial Report, August 31, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Coordinating Board: Financial Report, August 31, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Coordinating Board: Financial Report, August 31, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Coordinating Board: Financial Report, August 31, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Coordinating Board: Financial Report, August 31, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Coordinating Board: Financial Report, August 31, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Coordinating Board: Formulas for Public Senior Colleges and Universities (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Coordinating Board: General Correspondence, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Coordinating Board: Guide for New Members (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Coordinating Board: Index of Minutes, September 1, 1969 - August 31, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Coordinating Board: Index of Minutes, September 1, 1970 - August 31, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Coordinating Board: Index of Minutes, September 1, 1971 - August 31, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Coordinating Board: Index of Minutes, September 1, 1972 - August 31, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Coordinating Board: Index of Minutes, Septmenber1, 1973 - August 31, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Coordinating Board: Minutes, October 17, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Coordinating Board: Minutes, February 9, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Coordinating Board: Miscellaneous Financial Info (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Coordinating Board: Miscellaneous Papers (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Coordinating Board: Miscellaneous Travel Info (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Coordinating Board: Miscellaneous Shorthand Notes (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Coordinating Board: Newspaper Articles/Clippings, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Coordinating Board: Newspaper Clippings - J.K. Williams (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Coordinating Board: Notes and Study Materials for Legal Education, November 22, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Coordinating Board: Pamphlets, Monthly Reports (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Coordinating Board: Presentation by the Dallas Chamber of Commerce (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Coordinating Board: Presentation Before Senate Finance Committee and House Appropriations Committee (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Coordinating Board: Proposal - Agricultural - Business Degree, July 18, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Coordinating Board: Proposal - Criteria for New Baccalaureate Degree Programs (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Coordinating Board: Proposal - Fiscal Regulations, July 19, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Coordinating Board: Proposal - Goals for the Expansion of Physical Facilities in Texas Public Higher Education (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Coordinating Board: Proposal - Outline for Developing Institutional Description and Projections (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Coordinating Board: Proposal - Research and Development Project, July 1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Coordinating Board: Proposal - State Commission (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Coordinating Board: Proposal - Texas Public Community/Junior College Association (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Coordinating Board: Public Hearings (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Coordinating Board: Recommendations, Suggestions and Tentative Outlines (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Coordinating Board: Report - Advisory Committee on Legal Education (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Coordinating Board: Report - Chrys Dougherty (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Coordinating Board: Report - Enrollment in the Music Area (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Coordinating Board: Report - Position Report on New Law School (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Coordinating Board: Report - Public Debt of the Public Senior Colleges and Universities and Medical Schools in the State of Texas (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Coordinating Board: Report - SHSH PhD Degree Program Request in Criminal Justice (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Coordinating Board: Report - State of Texas College Student Loan Program (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Coordinating Board: Report - The Status and Prospects of UTPB as an Upper Level Institution (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Coordinating Board: Report - Trends in State Funding in Higher Education (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Coordinating Board: Requests for Academic Programs and Administrative Changes (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Coordinating Board: Requests - Prairie View, TX - the Centennial Council (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Coordinating Board: Resolutions (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Coordinating Board: Rules and Regulation, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Coordinating Board: Staff Material (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Coordinating Board: Statements and Addresses (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Coordinating Board: Study - Health Science Library Resources in TX (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Coordinating Board: Study - Texas Formula System (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Coordinating Board: Study - The Availability and Use of Public Senior Higher education Facilities in Texas, January 1980 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Coordinating Board: West Texas Statutes and Codes (Box 3, Folder 35)